When you look at people that are depressed, or even
people just not where they wanna be, they have no
compelling future. Anyone can deal with a difficult today if
they have a compelling tomorrow. Yes. A compelling future is
everything. Because without that, you can have an aim, by
the way, but if it's not compelling, it's not gonna
do much. Well, and you demonstrate in the physiology of
your lectures that compelling aspect is possible and real. Yes.
Right, and— But I also get them to experience it
once again. If they just watch me, that, you know,
like, I'm not here to be their warm-up.
I'm a role model example. I'm not here to be
your guru. I'm here to be your friend. I have
some insights. You have insights. We can learn from each
other, right? But the idea of getting in a state
of mind where you're in a heightened state of consciousness
because your energy increases— think about it. When your energy
drops,
usually negative thoughts grow with that pretty massively, right? Yes.
Yes. Self-negative thoughts, thoughts about society. As you raise the
energy level, it's like plugging into a computer. You have
the greatest computer but not enough electricity. But if there's
full electricity, there's power there. And most of us have
gotten adjusted to a level of energy, especially post-COVID,
That we don't even realize because we're like fish in
water. It has dropped massively. When I walk around into
companies, that's why engagement became so important to me. There's
just not the same level engagement, and no one's trying
to deliberately do it. They were conditioned for 4 years
to sit still in front of a computer and do
anything, and many people before that weren't doing anything. It
just magnified it. But when the energy increases, that's my
first job. Your consciousness increases with that frequency of intensity.
When you said memory,
Okay, well, there's a physiological explanation for that. Okay, so
dopamine does 2 things.
It produces that feeling of enthusiasm. Yes. So it produces
that feeling of reward. But that's not all. Imagine that
there's a positive outcome and that produces some enthusiasm. Okay,
now imagine that there's a chain of neurological events that
led up to that positive outcome. Yes. Okay, what dopamine
does is encourage the neural systems that were active just
before that positive event occurred to grow. Yes. So now
that is— You're creating more wiring. And you're strengthening them.
Meaning you're strengthening whatever connections were used to— So going
from dial-up to, you know, so if you're, if you're
increasing the energy and you're, and you're simultaneously getting people
to configure their goals, and those 2 things are happening
at the same time, that should increase the probability that
the goals that they adopt will be instantiated permanently, permanently
into memory. And then it's also not exactly the kind
of memory that you would call to mind to talk
about. It's the kind of memory that you see the
world through. Yes. So that's a different— that's procedural memory.
It's completely different kind of memory. I get it. It's
the kind of memory that— so let's say you practice
applying a certain framework of interpretation to your circumstances. Okay,
that practice reconfigures procedural memory, and that's literally
the
rewiring of the system through which you view the world.
That's correct. And when you have a new view of
the world, you come up with new meanings.
And meanings, as you know, we both know, you did
Maps of Meaning. My entire life has been, you know,
I remember reading Man's Search for Meaning. I'm actually making
the film. And it was one of the books that
influenced me the most because the ability to find meaning
even in the most difficult time. And Viktor Frankl to
me is just a godsend to this planet. Yeah, yeah,
it's a great book. It's crazy. Yeah, it's great. If
you haven't read it, please, whoever you're listening, read it.
Or if you ever— anybody's ever read it, read it.
Yes, that's Man's Search for Meaning. Yes. Read that book.
It's incredible.
of your meanings change, your focus and your meanings change
when your energy shifts. And so it's so fundamental to
bring that energy up, and most people have no reference
for it in their body. You know, if you go
to our concert, I remember Pat Riley came to one
of our— who, you know, owns a piece of the
Miami Heat, who was an amazing coach. If you're not
familiar with the NBA basketball, one of the winningest coaches
in history, good friend of mine, known him for 30
years. And he came to one of our programs and
he said, Tony, this is like the 7th game of
the NBA championship, but it goes on for 4 days
and it's 13 hours a day. Right, right.
Right, right. So that vibrancy, and most people at the
game are cheering at times and not, this is an
experience in your body. That's why I do the number
of hours. That's why it's immersion. That's why it's multiple
days, 4 days or 6 days. And that's why it
has the lasting impact. But you're right, the dopamine circuits
are actually creating, what's the white matter in your brain?
The myelin, right? Creating the myelin. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Hope
and excitement are wonderful things, but you need competency as
well. And in order to have that, the hope can
get you started, give you the drive, the vision, the
aim, but you've gotta have the execution.
You have both the strategy
and you've got to have the execution that's practiced. Yeah,
okay, okay. So let's talk about that because you talked
about eliciting motivation
over a long period of time. So I'd like to
know more about how you— Or I would even say
the word, if I may, drive.
Because motivation is— the reason I use it, it's like
a warm bath. You should probably take a bath, but
it doesn't last, right? You should still do it. But
drive is like everyone is motivated. If you're overweight, you're
motivated to eat, right? Come on. I want to find
out what drives you, because if we unleash your drive—
What drives you towards the right aim? That's right. What
is it that will unleash you? That's what this experience
is about. That's different than just being motivated. Okay, so
let's walk— okay, so I have an exercise that people
can do online called Future Authoring, and one of its
steps— and I'd like you to tell me how this
compares to what you're doing in your seminars, in your
events. So
it's, it's a conditions of satisfaction exercise, or it's a,
it's a meditation and contemplation exercise, or it's a prayer.
You could think of all the— or a request for
revelation. But here's the, here's the idea. So it's, uh,
you can—
you imagine for a moment that you could have what
you wanted and needed in 5 years. Okay. But there's
a condition.
You have to know what it is and you have
to specify it. Okay, now then the question would be,
well, how are you gonna discover that? And the answer
is you ask yourself. It's like, okay, like what would—
it's like the Viktor Frankl scenario. Even hypothetically, what would
get me out of bed in the morning on a
very, very difficult day? Yes. Like what could I imagine
could come to me in my mind? That's something that
will keep you up late, get you up early. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. Make you feel fully alive. Yeah, well, what
would make you persevere in times of trouble? Exactly. Even
a more direct question. Okay, so
And by the way, I find, tell me if it's
the same for you, it's not just the aim or
objective, it's strong enough reasons. In other words, somebody say,
I wanna make a billion dollars, but they don't do
it. And they even envision to get excited about it,
a million dollars, whatever it is. I wanna have 3
perfect children. I wanna write a book, whatever. The secret
is reasons come first, answers come second. Once I know
what I want, I gotta figure out why. Yes. 'Cause
purpose is stronger than object. So the object may inspire
you, but what's gonna keep you going is strong enough
reasons when it's tough. What are the reasons? Okay, I
want this money for what? Well, I wanna provide a
home
home for my mom. Well, that's very different than I
just want to have this— Yes, definitely. Pieces of paper
with pictures of dead people on it, right? Yes. People
say, I want money. They don't want money. They want
an emotion. They want an impact. They want security, or
they want freedom, or they want to be able to
contribute, or they want to do something they think money
will give them more choices on, right? They don't want
the money. So I'm always trying to dig underneath to
figure out what is the— Yeah, that's the substructure. Exactly.
Yeah. Okay. So surface desire, right? And many people focus
on the surface desire, not knowing enough reasons to follow
through. That's why New Year's resolutions don't work. 91% of
them— I don't know what the latest
statistic is people don't follow through after 3 weeks. By
the time they're hearing us speak, if they had New
Year's resolutions, they're gone because they don't have the reasons
to push through and they don't have the strategy. It's
wonderful if you say, I want to see a sunset,
but if your strategy is start running east as fast
as you can, I don't give a damn how positive
you are, it's not going to work. Yeah, right. So
it's a combination of that aim, those values, that drive
you and I are talking about that ignite enough reasons
for it, and then the strategies to execute because You'll
eventually find your way there, but the speed at which
you do it is if— I believe in modeling. I
believe success leaves clues. My original teacher, Jim Rohn, taught
me that. He said, if someone is successful at anything,
they've got a great relationship and it's 20 years down
the line and they still do it, or they lost
weight and kept it off for 10, 10 years, or
they went from nothing to not just making money but
sustaining financial security and freedom for their family, they're not
lucky. They're doing something different than you are. So instead
of you trial and trial and error, which standard way
in which we learn. You find the pathway to power
by finding someone who's done it consistently and produced results.
That obsession within me has launched most of the books
I've written, most things I've done. It's like, I want
to know what— you know, this book was, how do
I help people with
the best breakthroughs in health, for example, life force and
energy? They take 17 years to go from the breakthrough
time to your clinician. Like, how do I shorten that
up? I'm going to interview 150 of the most brilliant
regenerative doctors in the world, Nobel Prize winners, and find
out what they're doing, give it to you right now.
Or I'm gonna finance— well, I can talk to you
finance about what I think, or I can go interview
50 of the smartest financial people in the history of
the world that are alive today and find out what
do they do. While they're different, I look for what
are the common strategies, elements, what, what is guiding this,
and then I can teach that. My billionaire client goes,
this is incredible, and the average person goes, This is
incredible because it's about— it's very much what you do.
It's finding the pathway, it's finding the DNA, it's finding
the codex of how to go from where you are
to where you want to be. But it is more
than just the aim that'll start you. Yeah. It's— you've
got to have the purpose or the reasons, or your
purpose. If it's somebody else's purpose, the reasons won't work.
Yes, it's not going to work. Right. And then you
need the strategies too, because that'll give you the drive,
and you will figure it out if you— are you—
if you can discipline your disappointment,
if you can push yourself beyond what most people give
up on, you're going to get there eventually.
But you'll get there 10 times faster if you can
say, wow, there's already a pathway that's been proven. Why
would I reinvent the wheel? I'll still bring myself to
it, my own uniqueness to it, but there's certain fundamentals
that if you do them, you're going to have economic
abundance. If you don't, you're going to have pain.
That's the purpose of stories. That's exactly right.